positivityblog.com 2019-12-28

# Privacy Policy

## Who we are

Our website address is: [https://www.positivityblog.com](https://www.positivityblog.com/).

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

We collect a minimum of personal data.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

### Contact forms

We use a WordPress plugin for the contact form on the Contact Page of this website. This plugin does not store any of the sent messages on our webserver or in a database. The message is instead sent to our email inbox at Gmail.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

We use dedicated security software that uses cookies to protect this website from attacks and malicious activity.

Google Analytics uses cookies to better understand how a visitor uses our website (explained in more detail below).

We are an affiliate of Bluehost webhosting and Clickbank and if you click one of our affiliate links then they will use cookies to better understand how a visitor uses their website. If a page on this website contains an affiliate link then that is clearly mentioned early on that page or near the affiliate link itself.

### Ads

We also use ads by Mediavine on this website. Medavine  uses cookies to serve ads to our users based their previous visits to our site or other sites on the internet. This site has no access to the data collected via these ad cookies or via the ads displayed.

### Analytics

We use Google Analytics to better understand what people look at one this website.

When someone visits the site then information about their visit such as what pages they looked at, how much time they spent on those pages and what country this visitor is browsing the site from is is sent in an anonymous form to Google Analytics.

This data only contains information about anyone who is browsing our website from your computer and there is no way to identify a specific individual from this data.

We ensure that no personally identifiable information is ever contained within the data sent to Google Analytics.

As analytics information is not personal data, we do not specifically ask for your prior consent.

### Email list addresses

If a visitor consents to joining one of our email lists such as the free to join Positivity Newsletter then they will be sent regular emails containing information about personal development and information about our premium courses. A few of the emails for the Positivity Newsletter contains affiliate links (these are clearly marked as affiliate links within the text).

To join an email list they need to put in their email address into one of the sign up forms on this website, click the “Sign Up” button below the email form and then they will be sent to a page were they will receive more detailed information about the content of the emails they can choose to receive. This page will also display a step-by-step guide for how the visitor can confirm his or her subscription to the email list by clicking a button in an email they have just been sent.

All the email lists on this website (one is free as mentioned above and the rest is connected to our premium course material delivery and course signup availability) are double optin email lists. This means that person subscribing has to click the button in the email that was sent to confirm their subscription. And this procedure is set in place to make sure we get that subscriber's clear consent to send him or her emails via the email list.

### Order forms

If a visitor joins one of the Positivity Blog premium courses then the payment processing for the course is handled by fastspring.com. They collect a minimum of information about the customer or more specifically the name, the email address and the payment information of the customer (such as the credit card number).

## Who we share your data with

No one. The data collected by this website is only accessed and used by the owner of this website  (Henrik Edberg).

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

If you send a message via the contact form on the Contact Page then that message is retained for 5 years.

If you join one of our email lists then your email address and associated data is retained until your cancel your subscription to that email list (either by using the unsubscribe link at the end of each email sent or by emailing us and requesting us to delete your email address from that email list). Or until your email address is deemed inactive (meaning that your email address has not opened one of our newsletters in at least 6 months) and is deleted manually.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have have left comments on this website or subscribed to one of our email lists then you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us.

You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## Your contact information

To contact Henrik Edberg – the owner of this website – about anything about your data please send an email by using the contact form on [the Contact page](https://www.positivityblog.com/contact/).

## Additional information

### How we protect your data

We take the security of personal data and this website very seriously.

The data collected is protected in a number of ways:

  *  **Access control:** The data is only accessed by one person, the owner of this website: Henrik Edberg.
  *  **Dedicated security software:**  We operate dedicated security scanning and access control software on this website. This software limits login attempts to our site, blocks potentially malicious attempts to access our services, and regularly performs full file system scans.
  *  **Data encryption:**  This website is secured with SSL encryption, which means that all traffic to and from our servers is encrypted. This also applies to our own administrative access to the website.
  *  **Selection of third party service providers:**  we use a minimal number of third party service providers, but some are essential for the provision of physical hosting environments and email list services. One of the core factors in the selection of such providers is their ability to provide secure systems and processes.

### What data breach procedures we have in place

As this website is run by one person (Henrik Edberg) are there no internal reports about a potential data breach. Security breaches is regularly scanned for by using dedicated security software and all programs used on this website are always updated to the latest version. If any data breach was to be detected then all other tasks are put on hold and the breach becomes the top priority to handle.

### What third parties we receive data from

We receive data about email list subscribers from Aweber.com that hosts all of our email lists. Such data could for example be what emails a particular and subscribed email address has opened or how long they have been subscribed to that a certain email list.

We can also access limited information about our customers that have joined the premium courses via fastspring.com's payment processing. That includes information about the name and email address of the customer but not the payment information (this is protected and safely stored by fastspring.com).
